# **CURRICULUM VITAE**



#### Personal information

Surname(s) / First name(s)

Address(es)

Telephone(s)

Email(s)

Date of hirth

# **Oprisan Andrei**

str Magura, nr 24, 550317, Sibiu, jud Sibiu, Romania

+40 748 75 75 95

aoprisan@gmail.com

April 17, 1982

# Personal skills and competences

SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

I have 11 years of experience in software industry and academia, with 4 years in the data security field, acting as product manager, software developer and architect.

In the last several years I have been working on the development of Business Intelligence SaaS applications. I have been handling a variety of technical tasks ranging from back-end services architecture and implementation using functional and object-oriented programming to multi-dimensional queries (MDX), databases and OLAP cubes configuration, from developing front-end GUI to integration strategies with different third party service providers: REST and SOAP, OAuth 1.0a and 2.0, JSON and XML.

Additional information can be found in my LinkedIn profile

http://www.linkedin.com/in/aoprisan

Romanian

THER LANGUAGES English (advanced)

# Additional information

PERSONAL INTERESTS

Literature, jogging, hiking, traveling, programming languages

## Education

TITLE OF QUALIFICATION AWARDED

DATES

ORGANIZATION

LITLE OF GRADUATE WORK

#### Master of Science in Computer Science

September 2006-September 2008

Department of Computer Science, Faculty of Science, University of Joensuu, Joensuu, Finland «Aspect Oriented Implementation of Design Patterns using Metadata »

ftp://cs.joensuu.fi/pub/Theses/2008\_MSc\_Oprisan\_Andrei.pdf

TITLE OF QUALIFICATION AWARDED

DATE

ORGANIZATION

TITLE OF GRADUATE WORK

**Diploma Engineer, Computer Engineering** 

September 2001–June 2006

Universitatea Tehnică "Gh. Asachi" din Iași

«Web-based E-Learning platform»

### Work experience

Occupation or position held

Dates

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Main activities and responsibilities

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

TYPE OF BUSINESS OR SECTOR

OCCUPATION OR POSITION HELD

DATES

NAME AND ADDRESS OF EMPLOYER

Type of business or sector

#### Software Architect and CTO, Co-Founder

December 2011-Present Time

Smeebi Ltd., Espoo and Joensuu, Finland

Software Development of Business Intelligence Systems

- Software project management, design and development using agile techniques, functional and object-oriented programming
- Technologies evaluation and business development
- Backe-end architecture and development
- Integration strategies with different service providers: REST and SOAP WS, OAuth 1.0a and 2.0, JSON and XML
- Working with remote teams
- Test Driven Development: Specs2
- OLAP cubes configuration and data transformation routines
- Development primarily with Scala, Clojure/ClojureScript, JavaScript, Postfgresql, MySql, Mondrian, MDX, Play 2.x, SBT, Github, Heroku on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

#### **Technical Consultant**

December 2011-Present Time

Obsidian Innovations Ltd., Espoo, Finland

Software Development and Consultancy

- Design and development of a financial analysis application
- Technology evaluation, business development, project planning
- Back-end architecture and development
- Developing dashboards and reports for daily trading
- Object-oriented programming, functional programming, software architecture, Test Driven Development, web development, cloud computing
- Development primarily with Scala, JavaFX, Java, Clojure, JavaScript, Maven, JasperReports, Talend ETL, SBT, Github on GNU/Linux, Windows 7

#### **Technical Product Manager**

March 2011-December 2011

Blancco Ltd., Helsinki and Joensuu, Finland

Development, distribution and maintenance of data destruction software systems

- Development of data destruction application
- Involvement in the gain of Data Security top certificates
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac

# Occupation or position held Dates

Main activities and responsibilities

#### Senior Software Engineer / Software Engineer

June 2007-February 2011

- Blancco Data Cleaner design and development
- Design and development of data destruction application (hardware communication, data destruction engine, remote API, graphical user interface)
- Object-oriented programming, architecture design, Test Driven Development, Continuous Integration
- Agile development using Scrum
- Enabling the adoption of Test Driven Development practices in the company
- Bringing latest industry trends in the product development process
- Working with remote development teams
- Development primarily with C, CVS, GNU tool-chain, Valgrind, Bash, Emacs, Linux Kernel 2.4-2.6, C++, Qt framework, GNU tool-chain, SVN, Trac